Finding aid for the Alfred Shaughnessy papers, 1964-1996 LSC.2273
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alfred Shaughnessy papers
1964-1996
1971-1975
UCLA Library Special Collections
Shaughnessy, Alfred
LSC.2273
1.4 Linear Feet (2 document boxes, 1 half document box, and 1 flat box)
This collection contains material related to the script writer and editor Alfred Shaughnessy and his work for the British television series Upstairs, Downstairs (1971-1975).
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of David Shaughnessy, 2006.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9976707163606533
Biography
Alfred Shaughnessy (born May 19, 1916, London) was the chief writer and script editor of Upstairs, Downstairs, the British television drama series about the lives of an Edwardian London family and their loyal servants. The series, originally produced by London Weekend Television (LWT), ran from 1971-1975 on ITV. Alfred Shaughnessy wrote a third of the scripts for Upstairs, Downstairs, which was widely acclaimed for its social commentary; his aristocratic upbringing was credited for the historical accuracy of the series. Alfred Shaughnessy died November 2, 2005.
Scope and Content
This collection contains material related to the script writer and editor Alfred Shaughnessy and his work for the British television series Upstairs, Downstairs (1971-1975). Material includes scripts, production plans, publications and clippings, and photographs.
Arrangment
This collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Scripts
Series 2. Production material
Series 3. Photographs
Series 4. Publications and clippings.
Upstairs, downstairs (Television program: 1971-1975); Television Programs -- Great Britain; Television scripts -- Archives.
- Series 1. Scripts, [1971-1975]
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains 13 Upstairs, Downstairs scripts, written by Alfred Shaughnessy, for episodes broadcast between 1972 and 1975. Dates are those of first broadcast.
  - Episode list & list of countries where Upstairs, Downstairs is being shown (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Season 1, Episode 10: Why is Her Door Locked?, 1972 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    Scope and Content
    Director: Brian Parker; recorded: 1971 Mar 12.
  - Season 2, Episode 2: A Pair of Exiles, 1972 Oct 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Director: Cyril Coke; recorded: 1972 Jun 6.
  - Season 2, Episode 13: A Family Gathering, 1973 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Director: Ray Menmuir; recorded: 1972 Dec 8.
  - Season 3, Episode 12: Distant Thunder, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Director: Bill Bain; recorded: 1973 Dec 7.
  - Season 4, Episode 4: Women Shall Not Weep, 1974 Oct 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Director: Chris Hodson; recorded: 1974 May 17.
  - Season 4, Episode 9: Another Year, 1974 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Director: Cyril Coke; recorded: 1974 Jul 12.
  - Season 4, Episode 14: Peace Out of Pain, 1974 Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Director: Chris Hodson; recorded: 1974 Sep 20.
  - Season 5, Episode 1: On With the Dance, 1975 Jan 10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Director: Bill Bain; recorded: 1975 Jan 10.
  - Season 5, Episode 4: The Joy Ride, 1975 Sep 28 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Recorded: 1975 Feb 21.
  - Season 5, Episode 7: Disillusion, 1975 Oct 19 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Director: Bill Bain; recorded: 1975 Apr 4.
  - Season 5, Episode 10: Alberto, 1975 Nov 16 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Director: Chris Hodson; recorded: 1975 May 16.
- Series 2. Production material, 1971-1983, undated
  Series consists of cast lists, production plans and notes, a treatment for a stage musical version of the show, transcripts of interviews with Shaughnessy, and a small amount of correspondence.
  - Cast Lists, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Production plans, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Contains a draft of the show's outline, the original pitch to LWT, and production plans for the series as a whole and for each season. Also includes season outlines and story element lists. Several items are heavily annotated.
  - Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Contract for episode rights, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Contains letters addressed to Alfred Shaughnessy and some fan club material.
  - Stage musical treament, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Transcripts, Shaughnessy interviews, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series 3. Photographs, Undated
  Contains cast photographs in black and white and one color, and some set photographs.
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5, Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series 4. Publications and clippings, 1964-1996
  - Newspaper Clippings, Beacon Hill, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Upstairs, Downstairs, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Magazines: Theater Quarterly, Movie, Television Mail, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Upstairs, Downstairs Remembered (LWT publication), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Magazine: Telegraph Sunday Magazine, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Magazine: TV Times, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Magazine: Woman, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Magazine: Woman and Home, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)